Mohamed Rafeek () Featured

Senior software engineer Looking for a challenging position on software engineering, software management in a reputable organization to utilize my 7 years Experience of interpersonal skills and technical as well as domain-based Development skills



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: OFS (Object Frontier software) Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: abu dhabi Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Chennai, United Arab Emirates (UAE)
Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer/Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Business Intelligence, Project Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Requirement

Gathering, Machine Learning, Spring Boot, Mongo DB, MySQL, Java

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Looking for a challenging position in a reputable organization to utilize my 7 years Experience of interpersonal skills and technical as well as domain-based Development skills to achieve goals of a company that focuses on customer satisfaction and customer experience.

Actively Working on E-commerce and Explicit semantic analysis, Penetration Bug Bounty projects by freelancing to enhancing RFM and vectorial representation of text using elastic search and BOW to reduce bandwidth and implementation of emerging technology Machine Learning.

Work Experience

OFS (Object Frontier software) as Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2019 to Till Date

Project: INTERNET/MOBILE BANKING) Client: ADIB (ABUDHABI Islamic Bank)

Tools and Technologies: Java 1.11, spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring cloud, Spring JPA, Spring

Integration, Spring Batch, Oracle PLSQL, Microservices architecture, in memory Cached DB, Redis, OpenShift, Docker, Jenkins, Windows Azure, XML EXTERNAL ENTITIES, IBM CIAM, DDOS. Developed a thorough understanding of business and functional requirements for internet and mobile and multiple channels accessing banking application API. Lead the development team and own all application deliverables. Ensure the timely

implementation of all technology and business mandated implementations

KNTX Trading solutions - Rs software as Senior Software Engineer Jan 2018 to Oct 2019

Project: Unified Payments Interface (UPI)

Client: NPCI (National Payments Corporation of India)

Tools and Technologies: Java 1.8, spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring JPA, Spring Integration, Spring Batch, Microservices architecture, in memory Cached, Redis, Kubernetes, Spring cloud,

PostgreSQL, NOSQL, XML EXTERNAL ENTITIES.

1/22/2021

Successfully delivered and migrated UPI 2.0 and implemented lightweight workflow framework written over spring framework and delivered earlier of Cut-off time and ensured stability as well as reduced failure transactions.

al amtar systems as Contract Engineer

Jun 2017 to Dec 2017

Have done migration project from monolithic to microservices for short time contract in oman

L&T Infotech as Software Engineer

Feb 2015 to May 2017

Worked in development and

migration of java web applications and was being a part of CitiDirect Online Banking project development and automation in BFS (Banking and Financial Services) Domain for the client Citibank. Project: Citi Direct Online Banking.

Client: Citi Bank

Tools and Technologies: Java 1.8, Python, spring Boot, Spring Batch, PCF, Hibernate, Oracle PI SQL, RESTful API web, Agile.

Application Development, work with DevOps and Production support team to enhance application feature enhancement and find maximum possibilities of manual work to automated.

Geetham Software as Software Engineer

Jan 2014 to Jan 2015

| was working in various client and various domain gathered vast knowledge of development and migration of java web applications and was being a part of CitiDirect Online Banking project development and automation in BFS (Banking and Financial Services) Domain for the client Citibank. Project: Citi Direct Online Banking.

Client: L&T infotech (Citibank)

Tools and Technologies: Java 1.8, Python, spring Boot, Spring Batch, PCF, Hibernate, Oracle PI SQL, RESTful API web, Agile.

Application Development, work with DevOps and Production support team to enhance application feature enhancement and find maximum possibilities of manual work to automated.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Sri kaliswari college, sivakasi in 2011

PG: MCA (Computers) from Crescent Engineering College, Chennai in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Spring Boot, Spring Security,			
Spring JPA, Django, Python,			
Apache Kafka, Redis Events			
Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL,			
Redis, Mongo DB, NOSQL,			
Linux (Ubuntu and Kali), Mac.			
Core Java , Microservices , spring boot	5	2021	7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
0 0	,			•	

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=6b41c777c14169d1281d6f45cb6ff05c5c0f585048415f405014495c5f09...

English	Expert
Tamil	Expert
French	Proficient

Affirmative Action

Category: OBC - Creamy Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Countries: United Arab Emirates Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time